Finding Aid for the Katherine Philips Edson Papers LSC.0235
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence (1921-1933)
  - (January-October 1921), 37 pieces
    - John B. andrews., Child labor legislation, U.S. Supreme Court. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mabel Willebrandt., Thanks for support in gaining Assistant Attorney Generalship. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mary anderson., Minimum wage legislation and women's organizations. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Anne M. Mumford. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - John B. andrews., Minimum wage legislation. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mabel Willebrandt., Attitude toward a woman assistant attorney general. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - (November-December 1921), 79 pieces
    - (telegram) Clara B. Burdette., Congratulations on appointment to Advisory Committee of the Conference on the Limitation of Armament, Washington, D.C. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Martin A. Meyer., Congratulations on appointment. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Martin A. Meyer., Speaking engagement. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Meyer Lissner., Congratulations on appointment. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - David J. Reese., Congratulations. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - E. Clemens Horst. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - E. Clemens Horst--Warren Harding., Foreign loans, article: Frenzied Foreign Financing, in San Francisco Daily Commercial News. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Charles Evans Hughes., Notice of appointment of Katherine Philips Edson to American Advisory Board of the disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Edith Walker Maddux., Congratulations from California Civic League. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - P.O. Rowe., Congratulations. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Harriet Taylor Upton., Congratulations. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Harriet Taylor Upton., Expenses of trip. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Charles Evans Hughes., Expenses. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Clara B. Burdette., Announcing arrival, League of Women Voters. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Welfare Commission secretary--A.B.C. Dohrmann. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mabel Willebrandt., Objection to Woman's Party's proposed equal rights amendment. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Dr. James H. McBride., Congratulations on appointment. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Marian Mel. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. W.H. Udall., Congratulations, League of Nations, Charles Evans Hughes. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Marie Stuart Edwards., Congratulations, League of Women Voters, Mrs. Livermore and Ruth McCormick, Harriet Taylor Upton. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Congratulations. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Marian (Mel?). (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Beatrice Volkman., Congratulations from Woman's Athletic Club of San Francisco. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Florence C. Fox., Invitation to speak on education. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Marthe S.F. Bent., Disarmament conference, Mary S. Gibson. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald., Los Angeles conferences, Walter Mathewson. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Lou Henry Hoover., Invitation to dinner. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - F. Eldred Boland., Congratulations. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Anne Forrestal., League of Women Voters' invitation. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - William J. Beeson., Disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald., Senate joint resolution. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mary Jackson Moore., Disarmament conference, India. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - William Draper Lewis--Mildred J. Gordon., Proposed equal rights amendment. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Phebe P. Scott., Disarmament conference, against poison gas and submarines, etc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Franklin R. Davenport, Agnes E. DeMonde, Anabel P. McCamp, James S. Bryan., Disarmament conference, urging freeing of political prisoners everywhere. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Margaret B. Curry., San Francisco Federation of Women's Clubs' views on disarmament conference, against poison gas, Jennie Partridge. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mary E. Dreier., National Women's Trade Union League's views on disarmament conference, submarines. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ruth V. Tibbals., San Diego Women's Civic Center's views on disarmament conference, chemical warfare. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Berkeley Committee, Women's League for Peace and Freedom., Disarmament conference, submarines, chemical warfare, etc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Elsie Lee Turner., Disarmament conference proposals. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. W.H. Udall., Woman's Club of Tacoma's views on disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Marian L. Mel. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - M.E. Pownall., Disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Melva S. Green., California Women's Christian Temperance Union, disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Faevea Harlan, for Florence K. Harding., Invitation to lunch. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. Henry A. Whitmarsh., Rhode Island League of Women Voters, disarmament conference, Warren G. Harding. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Welfare Commission clerk--A.B.C. Dohrmann. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mary Haney., Woman's Trade Union League of Chicago, disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - William H. Holly--Agnes Nestor., Proposed equal rights amendment and protective legislation. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Harold L. Ickes--Agnes Nestor., Proposed equal rights amendment and protective legislation. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mary Morrisson. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ethel M. Smith., Women's welfare laws, prominent attornies' opinions of proposed equal rights amendment, Dr. Alice Hamilton. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ethel M. Smith--Alice Paul., Proposed equal rights amendment, National Woman's Party, effects of proposed amendment on protective legislation for women. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Charles G. Curtis-- Ethel M. Smith., Proposed equal rights amendment, Maud Younger. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mary anderson., Proposed equal rights amendment, Woman's Party, Ethel M. Smith, Mrs. Kelly, Alice Paul, Maud Younger. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mary anderson-- Maud Younger., Proposed amendment, Felix Frankfurter, Roscoe Pound, Ernst Freund. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mary I. Stille. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Western Union-- Elizabeth Macdonald. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Powell Butte Sarosis Club., Disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Dora A. Stearns., Speaking invitation from Woman's City Club of Los Angeles. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) A.B.C. Dohrmann., California wage boards. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Welfare Commission clerk-- A.B.C. Dohrmann. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. H.O. Whitman., Pendleton (Oregon) Woman's Club's views on disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - (1922), 116 pieces
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald., Industrial Welfare Commission work, cost of living public conferences, minimum wage, J.R. Millar and California Manufacturers Association. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Alice M. LeRoy., Mount Scott Mental Culture Club (Oregon) views on disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - H.H. Lund., Asking for help in being cleared of slander, Warren Harding. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) George H. Sutherland-- A.B.C. Dohrmann., Katherine Philips Edson to remain longer at conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) A.B.C. Dohrmann., Going ahead with wage board. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald., Labor council in California and minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) Ethel R. Palmer., Invitation to speak. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Stephen G. Porter., Vacation trip, Ernest Thompson Seton. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bertha Cherry., Ladies Home Bureau of Umatilla's views on disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) Tsai Ting Kan., Speaking date. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Maud M. Miles., Disarmament conference proceedings after Katherine Philips Edson's departure, Mrs. Charles Sumner Bird's luncheon. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mary F. Leddy., Meyer Lissner. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Overlook Woman's Club., Disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Indiana Women's League of Voters., Disarmament conference, Warren Harding, Charles Evans Hughes. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - William P. Lucas. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Aggie Ginn Gould., Disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Maud M. Miles., Mrs. Egan. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - John H. Wigmore-- Agnes Nestor., Proposed equal rights amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Addie E. Harman., Ladies Rural Club (Oregon) views of disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Meyer Lissner., Katherine Philips Edson's considering a job change, Maud Miles. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) Ethel R. Palmer. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - George Christian, Jr., Acknowledgment of message to Warren G. Harding. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mattie B. Miller. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - R. Justin Miller., Service of women on juries. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Frank R. Devlin. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Frank Devlin-- Hiram Johnson., Katherine Philips Edson's speech on disarmament conference, supposed criticism of Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Kathleen Lawler., Fight over seating of Senator Newberry, Knicker-bocker disaster, Hiram Johnson, Chauncey Brainerd, Senator William E. Borah, Chief Justice William Howard Taft. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Maud M. Miles., Disarmament conference, Basil Miles, Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., Four-Power Treaty, imperialism and future of democracy in U.S., Chester Rowell, Woodrow Wilson, Senator Henry Cabot Lodge, Charles Evans Hughes. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Stephen G. Porter., Four-Power Treaty, Treaty of Versailles, Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Anne Morgan. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cornelia Pinchot. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - R. Justin Miller., Women jurors, Gail Laughlin. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - William McNeir. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - John Francis Neylan., Woman's Party, proposed equal rights amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Grant Jackson., Woman's Party, proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Gavin W. Craig., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Frank M. Angelotti., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Stephen G. Porter., Disarmament conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Frank R. Devlin, Douglas Brookman., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - James A. anderson., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - William D. Denman., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - G.S. Arnold., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Henry W. Louis., Minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Henry W. Louis., Minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - James A. anderson., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Gavin W. Craig., Proposed amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Henry W. Louis., Industrial Welfare Commission, labor opposition to lower minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bertha von der Nienberg., Emery and Millar investigations of Miss Nienberg, Industrial Welfare Commission, presidential appointments, Labor Secrettary James J. Davis, Florence Kling Harding, Raymond and Margaret Dreier Robins. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Harris Weinstock., Industrial Welfare Commission and minimum wage, labor opposition to lower minimum. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - A.B.C. Dohrmann., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Industrial Welfare Commission staff., Moral support for Katherine Philips Edson under attack on minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Dora Haynes., Attack on Industrial Welfare Commission and Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - J.C. Pinkerton., Attack on Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mary anderson., Attack on Industrial Welfare Commission and minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mabel Still, Adele Sterling, Daisy Houck., Protesting attack on Katherine Philips Edson and Industrial Welfare Commission on behalf of Garment Workers Local 125. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Garment Workers., Reduction of minimum wage, attack on Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Local 125-- Central Labor Council. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - R....P.... M.... (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - F.E. Laney., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) Mary anderson. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Helen Ring Robinson., Article on women in politics, Annette Adams. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) D.K. Johnston. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Henry W. Louis., Industrial Welfare Commission, Daisy Houck. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - John I. Nolan., Industrial Welfare Commission, minimum wage change, business competition between states, manufacturers' attitude toward protective legislation, O'Connell, J.R. Millar. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., Proposed constitutional amendment on Congressional regulation of child labor. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mary anderson., Labor unions, AFL, John I. Nolan. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mary anderson-- James J. Davis., California minimum wage reduction and labor reaction. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Labor unions, Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - John I. Nolan., California labor legislation and out of state competition, proposed child labor amendment. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Zelta Feike., Speaking engagement. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Enoch A. Bryan. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Gifford Pinchot. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mary anderson., Minimum wage legislation in different states, proposed equal rights amendment, Maud Younger, Frank P. Walsh. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Will H. Hays. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Four-Power Pact. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Marshall Stimson., Hiram Johnson, Herschel L. Carnahan, primary election. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., Primary election. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Edgar A. Luce., Asking for recommendation for federal judgship. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Edgar A. Luce., Recommendation, Mabel Willebrandt. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Arthur Keetch., Reappointment of Katherine Philips Edson to Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mary anderson., U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau work, women in industry conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - James J. Davis-- Mary anderson., Women in industry conference, protective legislation for women program of conference on women in industry. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Florence Prag Kahn., Women in industry conference. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Edith Walker Maddux. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Gifford Pinchot. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Grace M. Haring. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - California Federation of Women's Clubs-- William D. Stephens., Appreciation of Katherine Philips Edson's appointment to Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Jane I. Sullivan., Criticizing Katherine Philips Edson and Industrial Welfare Commission lowering of minimum wage, discussing living costs and wages. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., John T. Adams, Warren Harding, Senator Atlee Pomerene's fighting appointment for George Upton, meeting of women of the Republican Executive Committee, Mrs. Manley Fosseen, Ruth McCormick, etc., party organization. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - (1923), 62 pieces
    - Marian Mel. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hiram Johnson., Proposed child labor amendment, U.S. Supreme Court, William Howard Taft, William D. Stephens' governorship. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Chester Rowell-- Hiram Johnson., Johnson and Rowell's opinions on League of Nations and Hughes-Root-Taft plan. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - G(ertrude?) E. B(eebe?)., Women in industry conference, National Woman's Party, Florence Kelley. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) Gertrude E. Beebe. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson., Supreme Court brief. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Chester Rowell., California Under William D. Stephens' governorship, Friend Richardson, Gil Daniels, Progressivism in the midwest, Robert La Follette, Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Samuel Leask-- Marian Mel., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald., Industrial Welfare Commission representation at meeting. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Alice D. Gunst. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Samuel Leask., Industrial Welfare Commission, Marshall Hale. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) Alfred E. Raas-- Friend Richardson., Industrial Welfare Commission endorsement. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Richard M. Neustadt., Industrial Welfare Commission endorsement. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - I.B. Simon. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - I.B. Simon-- Friend Richardson., Industrial Welfare Commission endorsement. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Mabel Willebrandt., Willis I. Morrison's near nomination and other judicial appointments, Nellie Pierce's efforts against women's projects, Governor Friend Richardson's administration. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Willis I. Morrison., Unconstitutionality declared of minimum wage, Mabel Willebrandt, Senator Harry New, Judge William James' appointment to position sought by Morrison. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Willis I. Morrison--Hiram Johnson., Morrison's unsuccessful candidacy to federal bench in California, Johnson's possible candidacy for president. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Rulon S. Smoot., Minimum wage decision of Supreme Court. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - E.W. Reynolds, Company., Industrial Welfare Commission regulations. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Solomon Blum., Minimum wage decision. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Solomon Blum., Minimum wage, Industrial Welfare Commission, California Conference of Social Workers. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) The World., Asking Katherine Philips Edson's comment on statement by Nicolas Murray Butler concerning election issues. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Anna F. Eldridge., Minimum wage decision. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Pauline Goldmark. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Helen V. Bary., Industrial Welfare Commission work. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Helen V. Bary., Children's Bureau statistics on child labor. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - John C. Berendsen., Success poem by Robert Dollar. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Mabel Willebrandt., Minimum wage conference in New York, Florence Kelley, Felix Frankfurther, Supreme Court and minimum wage, Justice Oliver Wendell Holmes, Father John A. Ryan, Harriet Taylor Upton's loss of her husband. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., Washington conference, International Congress of Working Women. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Henry W. Louis., Industrial Welfare Commission's problems with new administration. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Josephine Littlejohn., Arizona Republican Party organization problems. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Henry W. Louis., Possible resignation of Katherine Philips Edson and A.B.C. Dohrmann from Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - E....R....P...., League of Women Voters meeting. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) Harriet Taylor Upton., Republican Party splits. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hiram Johnson., Warren Harding's death, Chester Rowell, Blaney's death. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) Marian Mel--Ethel Palmer., Asking for doctor's report on Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (telegram) Ruth Mount--Marian Mel., Report on Katherine Philips Edson's tumor. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Edgar A. Luce., Asking for support in getting appointment to Southern California U.S. District Court. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Frank H. Boren., Industrial Welfare Commission work, minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Frank H. Boren--Marian Mel., Women's clubs interest in Industrial Welfare Commission, Helen Gainer minimum wage case. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Frank H. Boren., Proposed constitutional amendment on minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Alice A. Winter., World Court. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - John T. Adams., Republican National Committee meeting. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - (1924), 25 pieces
    - Mrs. Barclay Warburton., Asking for photograph of Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Helen M. Werner., Presidential possibilities, Republican Convention, election work, Calvin Coolidge, Hiram Johnson, William G. McAdoo, anderwoorf, Elizabeth Kenney, Works. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - (telegram) Edith Abbott., Invitation to speak on equal rights amendment. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Charles K. McClatchy., Asking help in rallying California delegation behind Hiram Johnson at Republican Convention, Calvin Coolidge. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - J.P. Rettenmeyer., Commonwealth Club and minimum wage, court decisions. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hiram Johnson., Johnson's campaign to win Republican nomination, political future, Republican Convention, William Crocker, Calvin Coolidge, Harry Chandler, Edward A. Dickson, Arnolds, Better America Federation. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ethel., Industrial Welfare Commission, Italy and fall of Mussolini government, fascism, French elections, Henriot. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Christopher M. Bradley., Powell's article on Supreme Court decision on minimum wage legislation. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - (telegram) Grace Abbott. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Henry W. Louis., Industrial Welfare Commission work. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Henry W. Louis--J.P. Rettenmeyer., Discussing effects of minimum wage, Industrial Welfare Commission, favoring U.S. minimum wage legislation. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Samuel Leask., Brief in Helen Gainer Case, Harvard Law Review, Powell's article, individual liberty and restrictions for general welfare. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - (telegram) Mabel C. Costigan., Robert La Follette-Wheeler campaign. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Charles L. Neumiller., Republican State Committee of California, Calvin Coolidge-Charles G. Dawes slate and Republican campaign. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - (1925), 17 pieces
    - Ruth McCormick., Medill McCormick and Illinois politics. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Grace Abbott., California ratification of child labor amendment, Farmers' States Rights League and anti-amendment propaganda. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Hiram Johnson., Appointment to Naval Acad emy of Marshall Edgar Dornin. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Hiram Johnson., League of Nations, Calvin Coolidge, Herbert Hoover. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Florence Kelley., Helen Gainer case, litigation on minimum wage, State Senator T.C. West. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Florence Kelley., Minimum wage cases. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Mabel Willebrandt., California politics, Hiram Johnson's political plans. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Mary R. Dinsmore--Mrs. H.H. Koons. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Hiram Johnson., Proposed minimum wage amendment, Felix Frankfurter, National Woman's Party. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Esther A. Dunshee. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Paul (?) Kelly(?)., Desiring to publish article on Industrial Welfare Commission for The Survey, Supreme Court's ruling on minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Florence Kelley., Minimum wage amendment, child labor amendment, annual meeting of National Consumer's League and opposition to above, Wadsworth-Garrett measure, Professor John R. Commons, Justice Oliver Wendell Holmes. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - A. Estelle Lauder--Florence Kelley., National Consumer's League work for minimum wage legislation. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Belle Sherwin., Proposed minimum wage amendment, child labor amendment, Wadsworth-Garrett resolution (to change the amending clause of the Constitution). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - (1926-27), 35 pieces
    - Florence P. Kahn., Women in Industry conference, problems of prohibition, Congressman Julius Kahn. (Box 3, Folder 7)